A Finding Aid to the Livingston L. Biddle, Jr. Papers, Circa 1940-2002, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Livingston L. Biddle, Jr. papers
circa 1940-2002
Archives of American Art
Biddle, Livingston, 1918-2002
AAA.biddlivi
Archival Resource Key
40.2 Linear feet
The papers of government arts administrator and novelist Livingston L. Biddle, Jr. (1918-2002) measure 40.2 linear feet and date from circa 1940 to 2002. The papers are comprised of biographical materials, correspondence, interviews, writings, numerous files reflecting his work to establish the National Endowment for the Arts (NEA), political committee files, personal legal records, printed materials, scrapbooks, and photographs. Throughout the collection are video and sound recordings.
Conditions Governing Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. Research Center. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Scope and Contents
The papers of government arts administrator and novelist Livingston L. Biddle, Jr. (1918-2002) measure 40.2 linear feet and date from circa 1940 to 2002. The papers are comprised of biographical materials, correspondence, interviews, writings, numerous files reflecting his work to establish the National Endowment for the Arts (NEA), political committee files, personal legal records, printed materials, scrapbooks, and photographs. Throughout the collection are video and sound recordings.
Biographical materials consist of awards; diplomas; genealogy records; resumes; and files for Biddle's work at Fordham, his nomination for the National Medal of Arts award, and about his second wife Catharina Baart. Correspondence is with family, friends, and professional and political contacts such as Jane Alexander, President Jimmy Carter, Armand Hammer, Nancy Hanks, Edward Kennedy, Lady Bird Johnson, Sandra Day O'Connor, Claiborne Pell, Robert Rauschenberg, Slava Rostropovich, and others.
Interviews with Biddle include transcripts, four sound recordings, and two video recordings of Biddle with R.A. Davis, Bob Edwards, Peter Jessup, Susan King, Bob Schieffer, and Louann Temple.
Among the writings are journals, articles, poetry, speech notes, manuscript drafts of Our Government and the Arts: A Perspective from the Inside and Sam Bentley's Island, one video recording of "Art/Work/USA" by Barbara Rose, and one sound recording of a film introduction entitled "The Eagle".
Files concerning the establishment and early years of the National Endowment of the Arts consist of correspondence; congressional briefing books, committee files, and reports; financial material; drafts of the National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities Act of 1965; one sound reel titled "Swearing-In of L.L. Biddle, Jr.," and three video recordings. Additional files concerning Biddle's work for congressional committees and political campaigns include correspondence, meeting agendas and notes, and printed material concerning multiple arts organizations and the political campaigns for Jimmy Carter, Walter Mondale, and Claiborne Pell. Family and real estate records, a partnership agreement, and will are in personal legal records.
Printed materials include booklets, clippings, event invitations and programs, flyers, magazines and journals, and posters autographed by Jacob Lawrence, Fritz Scholder, and John Glenn. Additionally, one commercial sound cassette recordings of National Public Radio's program Performance Today is also found. Two mixed-media scrapbooks contain memorabilia from Biddle's professional life and international travel.
Photographs are of family, travel, and friends and colleagues at various events. Six video recordings are home movies of Bryn Mawr and documentaries about St. Katherine Drexel. Artwork in the form of pencil and watercolor sketches is by Ruth Asawa Lanier, Barb Maxwell, Pat Oliphant, James Rosenquist, and Howard N. Watson.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Livingston L. Biddle, Jr. papers were donated in 2013 by Thomas O'Callaghan, a close friend of Biddle's who inherited the papers.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 11 series.
Missing Title
Series 1: Biographical Material, circa 1950-2002 (2.5 linear; Box 1-3, 41, OV 43)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1956-2001 (2 linear feet; Boxes 3-5)
Series 3: Interviews, 1978-2002 (0.5 linear feet; Boxes 5-6)
Series 4: Writings, 1940-2002 (12 linear feet; Boxes 6-18)
Series 5: National Endowment for the Arts, 1964-2000 (10 linear feet; Boxes 18-27, 42)
Series 6: Committees and Political Campaigns, 1944-2001 (3.5 linear feet; Boxes 27-30)
Series 7: Personal Legal Records, 1952-1986 (1 linear foot; Boxes 30-31)
Series 8: Printed Materials, circa 1950-2000 (3.5 linear feet; Boxes 31-34, 41, OV 44)
Series 9: Scrapbooks, 1970-1998 (0.3 linear feet; Boxes 34, 42)
Series 10: Photographs and Video Recordings, circa 1950-2002 (4.6 linear feet: Boxes 34-40, OV 44)
Series 11: Artwork, 1976-1989 (0.3 linear feet; Box 40, OV 44)
Biographical / Historical
Livingston L. Biddle, Jr. (1918-2002) was a federal government arts administrator and novelist active in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania and Washington, D.C.
Livingston L. Biddle was born in Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania in 1918 to a distinguished and wealthy family. He graduated from Princeton University in 1940. During World War II, Biddle volunteered as an ambulance driver in Africa for the American Field Services.
While working as a special assistant to Rhode Island Democratic Senator Claiborne Pell in the 1960s, Biddle drafted the legislation for the National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities Act of 1965, which led to the creation of the National Endowment of the Arts (NEA) one year later. Biddle served as deputy chairman of the NEA from 1966 to 1967, as congressional liaison director in 1975, and as chairman from 1977 to 1981. In 1976, he served as director of the Congressional Subcommittee on Education, Arts, and Humanities.
Also a writer, Biddle wrote four novels, all set in Philadelphia, including Sam Bentley's Island published in 1961. From 1968 to 1970, he was a professor and chairman of Fordham University's arts division. Biddle also published a non-fiction book about his experiences establishing and working for the National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) titled Our Government and the Arts: A Perspective from the Inside in 1988.
Biddle married artist Catharina Baart in 1973 after his first wife, Cordelia Frances Fenton, died in 1972. Biddle died in Washington, D.C. in 2002.
Video recordings; Scrapbooks; Sketches; Authors -- Washington (D.C.); Diaries; Interviews; Manuscripts; Arts administrators -- Washington (D.C.); Photographs; Art -- Political aspects; Sound recordings; Transcripts; Drexel, Katharine Mary, Saint, 1858-1955; Davis, R. A.; Carter, Jimmy, 1924-; Biddle, Catharina Baart, 1912-2005; Asawa, Ruth; Alexander, Jane; Bryn Mawr College; Maxwell, Barb; Mondale, Walter F., 1928-; Schieffer, Bob; O'Connor, Sandra Day, 1930-; Fordham University; National Endowment for the Arts; Rauschenberg, Robert, 1925-2008; Scholder, Fritz, 1937-2005; Rostropovich, Mstislav, 1927-2007; Jessup, Peter, 1958-; Johnson, Lady Bird, 1912-2007; Watson, Howard N.; King, Susan; Lawrence, Jacob, 1917-2000; Temple, Louann; Edwards, Bob, 1947-; Glenn, John, 1905-; Hammer, Armand, 1898-1990; Kennedy, Edward M. (Edward Moore), 1932-2009; Hanks, Nancy; Pell, Claiborne, 1918-2009; Oliphant, Pat, 1935-; Rosenquist, James, 1933-
- Biographical Materials, circa 1950-2002; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-3, 41, OV 43
  Scope and Contents
  Biographical materials consist of appointment books, architectural plans of Biddle's property, certificates, keys to the city, plaques, diplomas, genealogy records, resumes, material from Biddle's tenure in the art department of Fordham University, Princeton University reunion records, and material regarding Biddle's nomination for the National Medal of Arts. The file for Catharina Baart contains resumes and statements on her career as an artist.
  - Addresses, circa 1970-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Appointment Books, 1974-circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5-9)
  - Architectural Plans, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Awards, Certificates, 1976-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Oversized material housed in Box 41.
  - Awards, Keys to the City, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
  - Awards, Medals, 1980-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
  - Awards, Plaques, 1977-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
  - Awards, Plaques, 1977-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Awards, Trophy, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Baart, Catharina, circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Diplomas, 1978-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4-7)
    Oversized material housed in OV 43.
  - Fordham University, 1968-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Genealogy, 1976-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Membership Cards, 1979-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - National Medal of Arts Nomination, 1991-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Passports, 1974-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Princeton University, 1986-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Resumes, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Awards, Certificates from Box 1, Folder 11, 1976-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 41)
  - Oversized Awards, Plaques from Box 1, Folders 17-18, 1977-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 41)
  - Oversized Diplomas from Box 2, Folders 4-7, 1978-1980; circa 1950-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 43)
  - Oversized Genealogy from Box 3, Folders 1-3, 1976-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 43)
- Correspondence, 1956-2002; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Boxes 3-5
  Personal and professional correspondence is with Biddle's family; former NEA chairs and political figures including Jane Alexander, Presidnt Jimmy Carter, Armand Hammer, Nancy Hanks, Frank Hodsoll, Lady Bird Johnson, Edward Kennedy, John Murtha, Claiborne Pell, Roger Stevens, and Sidney Yates; and other notable figures such as Sandra Day O'Connor, Robert Rauschenberg, and Slava Rostropovich. The series also contains correspondence with the American Film Institute, Century Club, Drexel University, and Music Critics Association, Inc.
  - Family, 1956-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - A-C, 1956-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11-13)
  - Adams, Howard, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Adler, Warren, 2000-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Alexander, Jane, 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Allen, Janet, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - American Film Institute, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Art Barn Association, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Bannon, Kathleen, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Behunin, Alan, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Berman, Philip, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Berman, Dr. Ronald, 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Billington, Jim, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Carter, Jimmy, 1980-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Century Club, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Chalabi, Maha El-Khalil, circa 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Chevy Chase Club, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Christian Science Church, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - D-G, 1956-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Doll, Joe, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Drexel, George and Laura, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Drexel University, 1959-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Elizabeth Seton College, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ferris, Bill, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Fitzgerald, Geraldine, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Freudenheim, Tom L., 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Freund, Gerald, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Goodman, Roy, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Gray, Irma, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - H-I, 1961-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Hall, Ivan, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Hammer, Armand, 1979-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Hodsoll, Frank, 1981-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Huber, Richard, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - J-K, 1965-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Jagoda, Barry, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - James, A. Everette, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Johnson, Lady Bird, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Keeney, Barnaby C., 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Kennedy, Edward, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Kimche, Lee, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - King, Elaine, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Koch, Edward, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - L-M, 1965-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28-31)
  - Lewis, Boyd, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Lindfors, Viveca, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Martin, Roger, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Matthaei, Marcella, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Mayer, Richard, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Mooney, John David, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Moore, Donald A., 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Murtha, John, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Music Critics Association, Inc., 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - N-P, 1963-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - National Arts Magazine, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - National Fine Arts Heritage Fund, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - New York Public Library, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - O'Connor, Sandra Day, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Orbit Productions International, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Pell, Claiborne, 1964-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7-9)
  - Pro Musicis, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - R-S, 1961-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
  - Radice, Anne, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Randall, Tony, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Rauschenberg, Robert, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Rogers, Lida, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Rostropovich, Slava, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Seawell, Donald R., 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Sexton, Nanette, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Seybolt, George, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Stackelberg, Garnett, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - State Department, 1956-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Stevens, Roger, 1974-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Stone, Peter, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - T-V, 1973-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25-26)
  - W-Z, 1975-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Walnut Street Theatre, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - The Washington Gallery/Museum News, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - The Washington Post, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Wexler, Stephen, circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - The White House, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Wiener, Louis, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Woman's National Democratic Club, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Yates, Sidney, 1980-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Interviews, 1978-2002; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Boxes 5-6
  Interviews include transcripts, four sound recordings, and two video recordings of Biddle on CBS' Nightwatch and the Evening News with Bob Schieffer, WETA's Desert Island Discs with R.A. Davis, and other interviews with Bob Edwards, Louann Temple, Peter Jessup, and Susan King. Also found is an interview with Bobby Mitchell conducted by Marion O. Greene, Jr. and Kim McCullough.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged chronologically by year.
  - Interviews with Biddle, Archival Resource Key (Box 5)
    - CBS, Evening News by Bob Schieffer, Transcript, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - On At the Corcoran, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Interviews with Biddle, Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
    - WETA, Desert Island Discs by R.A. Davis, 1985; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - by Peter Jessup, Transcript, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - by Bob Edwards, 1988; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - CBS, Nightwatch, 1988; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - by Susan King, 1989; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - by Louann Temple, Transcript, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Interviews with Others, Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
    - Bobby Mitchell Interviewed by Marion O. Greene, Jr. and Kim McCullough, Transcript, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Writings, circa 1940-2000; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 12 Linear feet Boxes 6-18
  Writings by Biddle include journals, drafts for articles, essays, plays, and short stories; poetry and songs; speech notes; one sound recording and two video recordings; drafts for the novels "Biddle Tales," Sam Bentley's Island, and "The Triptych"; and drafts for Biddle's book about his experiences with the NEA titled Our Government and the Arts: A Perspective from the Inside. Writings by others include one video recording of Barbara Rose's film "Art/Work/USA," one sound recording of a film introduction entitled "The Eagle," and writings by Claiborne Pell.
  - Journals, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
  - Article, "The Channel Islands", circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Article, "Our Government's Support for the Arts: Nourishment or Drought," The Annals Journal, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Article, New York Times, Arts and Leisure Section, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Article, Washington Arts, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Article, "In Defense of the Arts Endowment," Cosmos Journal, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
  - Book, Our Government and the Arts: A Perspective from the Inside, circa 1988; Archival Resource Key; Includes 1 sound cassette (Box 6, Folder 16-21)
  - Book, Our Government and the Arts: A Perspective from the Inside, circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1-15)
  - Book Introduction, Congress and the Arts: A Precarious Alliance by Margaret Jane Wyszomirski, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Book Proposal, Art Book, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17-18)
  - Book Proposal, "Furor in the Arts", 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Book Review, The Journal of Arts Management, Law and Society, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Essays, Archival Resource Key (Box 8)
    - "Dickens and His Sense of Humor", circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Statements on the Arts, circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "Research in the Arts: A Conference on Policy Related Studies of the National Endowment for the Arts", 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - "Arts and the Cities," Urban Symposium on the Arts, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "President Lyndon B. Johnson: The Arts, Humanities, and the Cultural Values", circa 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "In Memoriam: Nancy Hanks", 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Statement to Task Force on Libraries and Memorials, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - "Art Debate" Symposium, 1989; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "Art for Whose Sake?" Symposium, 1989; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - "To Develop Excellence in the Arts," The National Endowments: A Critical Symposium, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - "A Tribute to Senator Pell", 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Funding Notes, Wolf Trap, circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Funding Notes, National Building Museum, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Novel, Sam Bentley's Island, circa 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Novel, Sam Bentley's Island, Correspondence, circa 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 15-17)
  - Novel, Sam Bentley's Island, Jacket Cover, circa 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Novel, "The Senator Runs", circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 19-27)
  - Novel, "The Triptych", circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1-14)
  - Novel, "The Triptych", circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1-16)
  - Novel, "The Triptych", circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1-17)
  - Novel, "The Triptych", circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
  - Novel, "Biddle Tales", circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1-17)
  - Novel, "Biddle Tales", circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Novel, "Biddle Tales", circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 6-18)
  - Play, "The Fabulous Fiftieth", 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 3-5)
  - Poetry, circa 1975-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 6-14)
  - Poetry, 1984-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1-10)
  - Publisher's Catalog Sample The Village Beyond, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Short Stories, Archival Resource Key (Box 15)
    - "Happy Birthday", circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - "Heirloom", circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - "Return to Sorrento", circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - "A Tour of the Battlefield", circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - "Chicken Pie with Wishbone", 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - "The Man on the Stairs", 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - "One Day Leave", 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - "An Orchid for Mary", 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - "The Return", 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - "The Surprise Witness", 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - "Criseyda", circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - "The Thorn in the Rose Garden", circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 23-25)
    - "Moving Megalopolis", 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - "La Vie Sportine", circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Short Stories, Archival Resource Key (Box 16)
    - "Man in a Box", circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1-2)